Guide to the Woolsey Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Woolsey family papers
1750-1969
1811-1921
MS 562
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
51.75
(105 boxes)
The papers document three generations of the Woolsey family. The most prominent figures in the collection are William Walton Woolsey (1766-1839), land owner and merchant in New York City; his son, Theodore Dwight Woolsey (1801-1889), Greek scholar, political theorist and president of Yale College; and Theodore Salisbury Woolsey (1852-1929), professor of international law at Yale Law School, son of Theodore Dwight Woolsey. The papers of William Walton Woolsey contain extensive business correspondence, ledgers, legal papers, documents relating to land sales in New York and Ohio, as well as family and personal letters. Since he was engaged in the importation of sugar, cotton and hardware, some of his business correspondence is political with discussions of the Jay Treaty of 1794, the problems of piracy, American neutrality in the 1790s and the general politics of the period. Important correspondents are Chauncey Goodrich, Archibald Gracie, Eli Whitney, Noah Webster, Elihu and Nathaniel Chauncey, Oliver Wolcott, Benjamin Tallmadge, Jedidiah Morse, James Roosevelt, John A. Schuyler, Comfort Sands, John Broome, and Nicholas Bayard. The papers of Theodore Dwight Woolsey contain his writings on Greek language and literature, the Bible, international law and the texts of his sermons.
Woolsey family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Edith Woolsey and Laura Heermance, 1954-1960; Ann La Farge, 1988; Stratford Historical Society, 1991 (Accession 2015-M-032); Louise Heermance Tallman, 1995 and 2005; and Richard C. Woolsey, 2008.
Existence and Location of Copies
Account book of a general store kept by George Woolsey also available on microfilm (137 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM113.
Scope and Contents
The Woolsey Family Papers contain 94 boxes of papers, spanning three generations (1760's to the first quarter of the 20th century), centered mainly around William Walton Woolsey (1766-1839), a prosperous land owner and merchant in New York City; his son, Theodore Dwight Woolsey (1801-1889), Greek scholar, political theorist, and president of Yale College; and Theodore Salisbury Woolsey (1852-1929), son of Theodore Dwight, who gained renown as professor of International Law at Yale Law School.
The Papers are important to the historian interested in the early development of political theory and international law in the United States, the history of higher education, and especially the history of Yale College during a most eventful period in its history (1846-1871). There are also materials pertinent to the ethical and religious attitudes of the day and their relation to higher education. There are important documents and correspondence pertaining to the Chamber of Commerce of New York City, the Manumission Society, and extensive business correspondence during the period 1787 to 1839. In addition to the materials relating specifically to the Woolsey family, there are a number of letters pertaining to some of the most prominent New England families Chauncey, Salisbury, Johnson, Winthrop, Hillhouse with whom the Woolsey's were related by marriage.
The Papers are arranged into nine series: CORRESPONDENCE, WRITINGS OF THEODORE DWIGHT WOOLSEY, WRITINGS OF THEODORE SALISBURY WOOLSEY, PRINTED MATERIALS & PHOTOGRAPHS, GENEALOGICAL RECORDS, FAMILY BUSINESS DOCUMENTS, WILLIAM WALTON WOOLSEY ESTATE and BUSINESS PAPERS, and THEODORE DWIGHT WOOLSEY-OTHER PAPERS.
The CORRESPONDENCE series consists of 32 boxes of approximately 15,000 letters, the greatest part of which, is that of Theodore Dwight Woolsey. For the most part, the correspondence is intra- and inter- familial, although there are a number of letters from prominent political, educational, and religious leaders of the nineteenth century. (See the Selected List of Correspondents in the appendix). The series is especially helpful in depicting Theodore Dwight Woolsey's tenure as president of Yale College from 1846 to 1871. In addition, there are interesting letters by faculty members, such as Benjamin Silliman and Noah Porter, as well as Theodore Dwight Woolsey's own observations about religion and comparative education written while he studied and travelled in Europe.
The 27 boxes which comprise the WILLIAM WALTON WOOLSEY BUSINESS PAPERS are of particular interest. In addition to the papers relating to the Chamber of Commerce of New York City and the Manumission Society, there is an extensive correspondence pertaining to the day-to-day activities of a merchant engaged in the importation of sugar, cotton, and hardware. Much of this correspondence is between Woolsey and his agents in New Orleans, various ports in the West Indies, Montreal, Liverpool, London, and on the continent. Some of this correspondence is political in nature and reveals the concern of businessmen with various aspects of local, state, and national legislation. Specifically, there are letters containing discussions of the Jay Treaty, the problem of piracy, American neutrality in the 1790's and again during the Jefferson and Madison administrations, various acts of incorporation, i.e., Merchants Bank of New York City and the Eagle Bank of New Haven, and the policies of the British and French governments as well as those of the United States which finally culminated in the War of 1812. There is also material in this series and in the series entitled, WILLIAM WALTON WOOLSEY ESTATE, pertaining to Woolsey's land holdings in New York and the Ohio Territory. Among the notable correspondents in this series are: Chauncy Goodrich, Archibald Gracie, Eli Whitney, Noah Webster, Elihu and Nathaniel Chauncey, Theodore and Timothy Dwight, Oliver Wolcott, Benjamin Tallmadge, Jeddiah Morse, James Roosevelt, John A. Schuyler, Comfort Sands, John Broome, and Nicholas Bayard.
Biographical / Historical
William Walton Woolsey was born in 1766, the son of Benjamin Woolsey, a prominent New York merchant, and Anne (Muirison) Woolsey. He, like his brother George Muirison Woolsey, became a merchant in New York City engaged in foreign and domestic trade and sugar refining. In addition, he was an important landholder both in New York and in the Ohio Territory.
In 1792 Woolsey entered into a partnership with his brother-in-law, Moses Rogers, a hardware merchant. Rogers was also engaged in sugar refining, a business Woolsey later developed into a considerable fortune. They were in fact among the very first to refine sugar on a large scale in America. In addition, Woolsey became in 1807 the second president of the Eagle Fire Insurance Company, one of the oldest companies in the city of New York. He was also named as one of the directors of the Merchants' Bank and helped to obtain for it a charter which saved the bank from an "Act to restrain unincorporated Banking Associations" that had been passed in the previous state legislature. It appears that Woolsey, a brother-in-law of Timothy Dwight, was also a secret partner in the firm of Dwight, Palmer and Company.
When Woolsey and Rogers dissolved their partnership in 1804, the latter apparently paid Woolsey a "very handson sum" not to engage in the iron and hardware trade in New York for ten years. Woolsey therefore moved to New Haven in order to continue his hardware business. He remained in New Haven, where he was also president of the Eagle Bank, until 1815, when he returned to New York and resumed his old business activities.
Woolsey was closely associated in business with his brother, George Muirison Woolsey (1772-1851), a merchant whose ships successfully evaded the blockade during the embargo and carried cotton abroad. He was, of course, under heavy bond to the government for each ship that left to go to another domestic port, but, apparently through an understanding with the Collector of the Port of Perth Amboy, he was able to send his ships to sea. He was compelled, however, to go to Europe in order to save his property from confiscation and himself from prosecution for violation of the embargo. For several years he resided in Liverpool "until the Custom house at Perth Amboy was burned and the bonds with it." It is not clear whether William Walton Woolsey was a partner to these events, there are, however, a number of letters to him from his brother while the latter was exiled abroad.
Woolsey was prominent in the social and political life of New York. He was a member of the politically powerful Chamber of Commerce of New York City, an organization important to the economic development of the city. In 1796 he was elected secretary, a position he held for many years, and from 1825 until his death in 1839, he served as vice-president. He also served for many years as president of the Merchants' Exchange Company. In 1817 he was appointed by the Supreme Court of New York as one of the appraisers of the property which became the Erie Canal and in fact he had hosted many of the early meetings organized to further the canal project. In addition, Woolsey was vice-president of the Manufacturing Society of New York, a member of the Board of Governors of the New York Hospital, treasurer of the American Bible Society, and a very active member in the Manumission Society. He was too a member of the Friendly Club, which flourished in New York for many years before and a few years after the death of Washington, until it was disrupted by political differences. The club, which included among its members Chancellor Kent, Gilbert Aspinwall, Charles Brockden Brown, Anthony Bleeker, and the historian, playwright, and painter, William Dunlap (Woolsey's brother-in-law), met every Tuesday evening in the home of one of the members for literary discussion.
Woolsey married twice, first to Elizabeth Dwight, sister of President Dwight of Yale College and the granddaughter of Jonathan Edwards, and, after her death in 1813, to Sarah Chauncey. He died in New Haven in 1839.
(For additional information see Old Merchants of New York by Walter Barrett (N.Y.: Carleton, 1863).)
THEODORE DWIGHT WOOLSEY
Theodore Dwight Woolsey, born in New York on October 31, 1801, was the son of William Walton Woolsey, a prosperous hardware merchant, and Elizabeth Dwight Woolsey. He was a nephew of Timothy Dwight and a grand-son of Jonathan Edwards. He moved with his family to New Haven in 1806, where he attended Hopkins Grammar School and graduated from Yale College in 1820, valedictorian of his class. After studying law with Charles Chauncey in Philadelphia, he studied at the Princeton Theological Seminary until 1823. He returned to Yale as a tutor in 1823 where he also completed his theological studies. He went to Europe in 1826 for four years where he traveled and studied Greek language and literature.
In 1831 he was appointed Professor of Greek language and literature at Yale College. In 1833, he married Elizabeth Martha Salisbury, by whom he had nine children. He devoted himself to the classics until 1846 when he was appointed to the presidency of Yale College. He declined it at first, doubtful of his religious fitness. Finally persuaded to accept, he was inducted into the presidency and ordained as a minister on October 21, 1846. At the start of his administration, he relinquished the teaching of Greek and began to teach History, Political Science and International Law. During the twenty-five years of his presidency Yale made greater progress than during any other previous administration.
Elizabeth Martha Salisbury died in 1852. Woolsey was remarried in 1854 to Sarah Sears Prichard, by whom he had four children. He retired from the presidency in 1871 at the age of seventy. After his resignation, he continued to instruct at Yale and was a member of the corporation until 1885. He died in 1889 at the age of eighty-eight.
Theodore Dwight Woolsey was the author of the following college text books: The Alcestis of Euripides, The Prometheus of Aeschylus, The Antigone of Aeschylus, and The Gorgias of Plato. He was also the author of three legal works: Introduction to the Study of International Law, Essays on Divorce, and Divorce and Divorce Legislation. He is also the author of A Volume of Sermons.
THEODORE SALISBURY WOOLSEY
Theodore Salisbury Woolsey was born in New Haven, Connecticut, on October 22, 1852, the son of Theodore Dwight Woolsey, then president of Yale College, and Elizabeth Martha (Salisbury) Woolsey. He entered Yale College at the age of fifteen. Upon graduation in 1872, he immediately entered the Yale Law School, where he remained, with the exception of a tour of Europe (1873-1875), until he received the degree of LL.B. in 1876.
In 1877 he was appointed instructor in public law in Yale College, and in 1878, he was appointed professor of international law in the Yale Law School, a position he occupied, with the exception of four years (1886-1890) of residence in California in order to improve his wife's health, until 1911.
Woolsey made his most notable contribution in the field of international law. In addition to the publication of J.N. Pomeroy's Lectures on International Law in Time of Peace (1886) and an enlarged edition of his father's Introduction to the Study of International Law (1891), Woolsey published many articles on specific international problems in professional journals, seventeen of which were published in 1898 under the title, America's Foreign Policy. Most of his time, however, was devoted to giving addresses and writing articles for popular journals in the attempt to persuade the American public of the significance of international law.
Woolsey was married on December 22, 1877, to Annie Gardiner Salisbury of Boston, by whom he had two sons. He died in New Haven on April 24, 1929.
SELECT LIST OF CORRESPONDENCE
Abbot, Ezra, 1819-1884
Adams, Henry Brooks, 1838-1918
Adams, John Pres., 1735-1826
Adams, William, 1807-1880
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916
Atwood, Charles B., 1849-1895
Bache, Alexander Dallas, 1806-1867
Bacon, Leonard, 1802-1895
Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, 1832-1907
Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
Baldwin, Simeon Eben, 1840-1927
Baldwin, Theron, 1801-1870
Bancroft, George, 1800-1891
Barnard, Frederick Augustus Parker, 1809-1889
Barnard, Henry, 1811-1900
Barnard, John Gross, 1815-1882
Bayard, Nicholas, 1644-1707
Beecher, Edward, 1803-1895
Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1889
Bidwell, Walter, Hilliard, 1798-1881
Binney, Horace (junior), 1780-1875
Boardman, Henry Augustus, 1808-1880
Bolles, Frank, 1856-1894
Bristed, Charles Astor, 1820-1874
Broome, John, 1738-1810
Brown, John Mason, 1837-1890
Buckingham, William Alfred, 1804-1873
Burritt, Elihu, 1810-1879
Campbell, William Henry, 1808-1890
Carrington, Henry Beebee, 1824-1912
Chamberlain, Daniel Henry, 1835-1907
Chase, Thomas, 1827-1892
Chauncey, Charles, 1777-1849
Chauncey, Elihu, 1840-1916
Chauncey, Nathaniel, 1789-1865
Clifford, John Henry, 1809-1876
Colden, Cadwallader David, 1769-1834
Cooper, Jacob, 1830-1904
Crosby, Howard, 1826-1891
Cushing, Caleb, 1800-1879
Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
Dana, Richard Henry, 1815-1882
Day, George E.'
DeForest, John Kinne Hyde, 1844-1915
Dexter, Franklin Bowditch, 1842-1920
Dexter, Henry M., 1821-1890
Dike, Samuel Warren, 1839-1913
Dodge, William Earl, 1805-1883
Dwight, Benjamin Woodbridge, 1816-1889
Dwight Sereno Edwards, 1786-1850
Dwight, Theodore William, 1822-1892
Dwight, Timothy, 1828-1916
Edwards, Pierpont, 1750-1826
Eliot, John, 1604-1690
Elliot, Charles William, 1834-1926
Evarts, William Maxwell, 1818-1902
Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
Farrand, Max, 1869-1945
Felton, Cornelius Conway, 1807-1862
Field, Cyrus West, 1819-1892
Field, David Dudley, 1805-1894
Field, Henry Martyn, 1822-1907
Fisher, George Park, 1827-1909
Garrison, William Lloyd, Jr.
Godkin, Edwin Lawrence, 1831-1908
Goodrich, Chauncey, 1759-1815
Gurney, Ephraim Whitman, 1829-1886
Hackett, Horatio Balch, 1808-1875
Harrison, William Henry, Pres., 1773-1841
Haven, Henry Philemon, 1815-1876
Hayes, Rutherford Birchard, 1822-1893
Heermance, Edgar Laing, 1833-1888
Henry, Caleb Sprague, 1804-1884
Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
Herrick, Edward Claudius, 1811-1862
Hitchcock, Henry, 1829-1902
Hoadly, George (junior), 1826-1902
Holt, Henry, 1870-1926
Hopkins, Samuel, 1807-1887
Howard, Oliver Otis, 1830-1909
James, William, 1842-1910
Jay, John, 1745-1829
Jefferson, Thomas, Pres., 1743-1826
Jessup, Henry Harris, 1832-1910
Johnson, Charles Frederick, 1807"
Johnson, William Samuel, 1795-1839
Johnson, William Woolsey, 1841
Keep, Norbert Porter, 1844-1907
Leavitt, Joshua, 1794-1873
Lee, Alfred, 1807-1887
Lieber, Francis, 1800-1872
Linn, William Alexander, 1847-1917
Lippincott, Joshu Ballinger, 1813-1886
Lloyd, Henry Demarest, 1847-1903
Lord, Daniel, 1795-1868
Madison, James, Pres., 1751-1836
Magoun, George Frederic, 1821-1896
Merrill, Seloh, 1837-1909
Morse, Jeddiah, 1761-1826
Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, 1791-1872
Packerd, Lewis Richard, 1836-1884
Palfrey, John Gorham, 1796-1881
Park, Edwards Amasa, 1808-1900
Peabody, Andrew Preston, 1811-1893
Perry, Arthur Latham, 1830-1905
Pierrepont, Edwards, 1817-1812
Pomeroy, John Norton, 1828-1885
Porter, Noah, 1811-1892
Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864
Robinson, Edward, 1858-1931
Rosenthal, Albert, 1863-1939
Ruggles, Samuel Bulkley, 1800-1881
St. Gaudens, Augustus, 1848-1907
Salisbury, Edward Elbridge, 1814-1901
Sanborn, Franklin Benjamin, 1831-1917
Sands, Comfort, 1748-1834
Scarborough, William Woolsey, 1819"
Schaff, Philip, 1819-1893
Schurz, Carl, 1829-1906
Scribner, Charles, 1821-1871
Sears, Barnes, 1802-1880
Seymour, Edward, 1835-1877
Shelton, Frederick William, 1815-1881
Silliman, Benjamin, 1816-1885
Sophocles, Evangeline Apostolides, 1805-1883
Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
Sprague, William Buell, 1795-1876
Stearns, William Augustus, 1805-1876
Storrs, Richard Salter, 1821-1900
Strong, Selah Brewster, 1792-1872
Stuart, Moses, 1780-1852
Taft, Alphonso, 1810-1891
Tallmadge, Benjamin, 1754-1835
Tappan, John, 1781-?
Tarbox, Increase Niles, 1815-1888
Taylor, Nathaniel William, 1786-1858
Thacher, Thomas Anthony, 1815-1886
Thayer, Joseph Henry, 1828-1901
Thompson, Joseph Parrish, 1819-1879
Trumbull, Henry Clay, 1830-1903
Trumbull, Lyman, 1813-1896
Twining, Alexander Catlin, 1801-1884
Villiard, Henry, 1835-1900
Ward, Henry Dana, 1797-1884
Ward, William Hayes, 1835-1916
Warren, William Fairfield, 1833-1924
Washington, George, Pres., 1732-1799
Watson, William, 1834-1915
Wayland, Francis, 1796-1865
Webster, Noah, 1758-1843
Weir, John Ferguson, 1841-1926
Wharton, Francis, 1820-1889
Whitaker, Epher, 1820-1916
Whitney, Eli, 1765-1825
Winthrop, Elizabeth (Woolsey), 1794-1863
Winthrop, William Woolsey, 1831"
Wolcott, Oliver, [1760-1833?]
Woolsey, Elizabeth Martha (Salisbury), 1812-1852
Woolsey, John Edward, 1803-1873
Woolsey, John Mumford, 1796-1870
Woolsey, Sarah Chauncey, 1835-1905
Woolsey, Sarah Sears (Prichard), 1824"
Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, 1801-1889
Woolsey, Theodore Salisbury, 1852 1929
Woolsey, William Walton, 1766-1834
Woolsey, William Walton, 1831-1857
Arrangement
Arranged in nine series and five additions: I. Correspondence. II. Theodore Dwight Woolsey - Writings. III. Theodore Salisbury Woolsey - Writings. IV. Printed Materials, Miscellaneous Writings, and Photographs. V. Genealogical Records. VI. Family Business Documents. VII. William Walton Woolsey Estate. VIII. William Walton Woolsey Business Papers. IX. Theodore Dwight Woolsey - Other Papers.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Other Finding Aids
For a partial listing of correspondents with the Woolsey family, please consult the Correspondents Index.
Armed Forces; Art; Business; Classical education; Cotton trade; Families; Greek language -- Study and teaching; Greek literature -- Study and teaching; International law; Law; Sugar trade; Travelers -- Europe; Women -- United States; Europe -- Description and travel; New Haven (Conn.); New Haven (Conn.) -- Social life and customs; New York (State); New York (State) -- Social life and customs; United States -- Commerce; United States -- Foreign relations; United States -- History -- 1783-1865; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; United States -- History -- French and Indian War, 1754-1763; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; United States -- Politics and government -- 19th century; United States -- Politics and government; United States -- Religion -- 19th century; Deeds; Sermons; Clergy; Abbot, Ezra, 1819-1884; Adams, Henry, 1838-1918; Adams, John, 1735-1826; Adams, William, 1807-1880; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916; Atwood, Charles B. (Charles Bowler), 1849-1895; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867; Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, 1830-1907; Bacon, Leonard, 1802-1881; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912; Baldwin, Simeon E. (Simeon Eben), 1840-1927; Baldwin, Theron, 1801-1870; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891; Barnard, Frederick A. P. (Frederick Augustus Porter), 1809-1889; Barnard, Henry, 1811-1900; Barnard, J. G. (John Gross), 1815-1882; Bayard, Nicholas, 1644-1707; Beecher, Edward, 1803-1895; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887; Bidwell, W. H. (Walter Hilliard), 1798-1881; Binney, Horace, 1780-1875; Boardman, Henry A. (Henry Augustus), 1808-1880; Bolles, Frank, 1856-1894; Bristed, Charles Astor, 1820-1874; Broome, John, 1738-1810; Brown, John Mason, 1837-1890; Buckingham, William A. (William Alfred), 1804-1875; Burritt, Elihu, 1810-1879; Campbell, William Henry, 1808-1890; Carrington, Henry B., 1824-1912; Chamberlain, Daniel Henry, 1835-1907; Chase, Thomas, 1827-1892; Chauncey, Charles, 1777-1849; Chauncey, Elihu, 1840-1916; Chauncey, Nathaniel, 1789-1865; Clifford, John H. (John Henry), 1809-1876; Colden, Cadwallader D. (Cadwallader David), 1769-1834; Cooper, Jacob, 1830-1904; Crosby, Howard, 1826-1891; Cushing, Caleb, 1800-1879; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895; Dana, Richard Henry, Jr., 1815-1882; Day, George Edward, 1815-1905; De Forest, J. H. (John Hyde), 1844-1911; Dexter, Franklin Bowditch, 1842-1920; Dexter, Henry Martyn, 1821-1890; Dike, Samuel W. (Samuel Warren), 1839-1913; Dodge, William E. (William Earl), 1805-1883; Dwight, Benjamin W. (Benjamin Woodbridge), 1816-1889; Dwight, Sereno Edwards, 1786-1850; Dwight, Theodore W. (Theodore William), 1822-1892; Dwight, Timothy, 1828-1916; Edwards, Pierpont, 1750-1826; Eliot, John, 1604-1690; Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926; Evarts, William Maxwell, 1818-1901; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865; Farrand, Max, 1869-1945; Felton, C. C. (Cornelius Conway), 1807-1862; Field, Cyrus W. (Cyrus West), 1819-1892; Field, David Dudley, 1805-1894; Field, Henry M. (Henry Martyn), 1822-1907; Fisher, George Park, 1827-1909; Garrison, William Lloyd, Jr., 1838-1909; Godkin, Edwin Lawrence, 1831-1902; Goodrich, Chauncey, 1759-1815; Gurney, Ephraim Whitman, 1829-1886; Hackett, Horatio B. (Horatio Balch), 1808-1875; Harrison, William Henry, 1773-1841; Haven, Henry P. (Henry Philemon), 1815-1876; Hayes, Rutherford B., 1822-1893; Heermance, Edgar L. (Edgar Laing), 1833-1888; Henry, C. S. (Caleb Sprague), 1804-1884; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878; Herrick, Edward Claudius, 1811-1862; Hitchcock, Henry, 1829-1902; Hoadly, George, 1826-1902; Holt, Henry, 1840-1926; Hopkins, Samuel, 1807-1887; Howard, O. O. (Oliver Otis), 1830-1909; James, William, 1842-1910; Jay, John, 1745-1829; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826; Jessup, Henry Harris, 1832-1910; Johnson, Charles Frederick, 1804-1882; Johnson, William Samuel, 1795-1883; Johnson, William Woolsey, 1841-1927; Keep, Robert P. (Robert Porter), 1844-1904; Leavitt, Joshua, 1794-1873; Lee, Alfred, 1807-1887; Lieber, Francis, 1800-1872; Linn, William Alexander, 1846-1917; Lippincott, J. B. (Joshua Ballinger), 1813-1886; Lloyd, Henry Demarest, 1847-1903; Lord, Daniel, 1795-1868; Madison, James, 1751-1836; Magoun, George F. (George Frederic), 1821-1896; Merrill, Selah, 1837-1909; Morse, Jedidiah, 1761-1826; Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, 1791-1872; Packard, Lewis R. (Lewis Richard), 1836-1884; Palfrey, John Gorham, 1796-1881; Park, Edwards Amasa, 1808-1900; Peabody, Andrew P. (Andrew Preston), 1811-1893; Perry, Arthur Latham, 1830-1905; Pierrepont, Edwards, 1817-1892; Pomeroy, John Norton, 1828-1885; Porter, Noah, 1811-1892; Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864; Robinson, Edward, 1858-1931; Rosenthal, Albert, 1863-1939; Ruggles, Samuel B. (Samuel Bulkley), 1800-1881; Salisbury, Edward Elbridge, 1814-1901; Sanborn, F. B. (Franklin Benjamin), 1831-1917; Sands, Comfort, 1748-1834; Scarborough, William Woolsey, 1819-; Schaff, Philip, 1819-1893; Schurz, Carl, 1829-1906; Scribner, Charles, 1821-1871; Sears, Barnas, 1802-1880; Seymour, Edward, -1877; Shelton, F. W. (Frederick William), 1814-1881; Silliman, Benjamin, 1816-1885; Sophocles, E. A. (Evangelinus Apostolides), 1807-1883; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866; Sprague, William B. (William Buell), 1795-1876; Saint-Gaudens, Augustus, 1848-1907; Stearns, William A. (William Augustus), 1805-1876; Storrs, Richard S. (Richard Salter), 1821-1900; Strong, Selah Brewster, 1792-1872; Stuart, Moses, 1780-1852; Taft, Alphonso, 1810-1891; Tallmadge, Benjamin, 1754-1835; Tappan, John, 1781-1871; Tarbox, Increase N. (Increase Niles), 1815-1888; Taylor, Nathaniel W. (Nathaniel William), 1786-1858; Thacher, Thomas Anthony, 1815-1886; Thayer, Joseph Henry, 1828-1901; Thompson, Joseph P. (Joseph Parrish), 1819-1879; Trumbull, H. Clay (Henry Clay), 1830-1903; Trumbull, Lyman, 1813-1896; Twining, Alexander C. (Alexander Catlin), 1801-1884; Villard, Henry, 1835-1900; Ward, Henry Dana, 1797-1884; Ward, William Hayes, 1835-1916; Warren, William Fairfield, 1833-1929; Washington, George, 1732-1799; Watson, William, 1834-1915; Wayland, Francis, 1796-1865; Webster, Noah, 1758-1843; Weir, John F. (John Ferguson), 1841-1926; Wharton, Francis, 1820-1889; Whitaker, Epher, 1820-1916; Whitney, Eli, 1765-1825; Winthrop, Elizabeth Woolsey, 1794-1863; Winthrop, William, 1831-1899; Wolcott, Oliver, 1760-1833; Woolsey, Elizabeth Martha Salisbury, 1812-1852; Woolsey, John Edward, 1803-1873; Woolsey, John Mumford, 1796-1870; Woolsey, Sarah Chauncey, 1835-1905; Woolsey, Sarah Sears Prichard, 1824-; Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, 1801-1889; Woolsey, Theodore Salisbury, 1852-1929; Woolsey, William Walton, 1766-1839; Woolsey, William Walton, 1831-1857; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Officals and employees; Yale University -- Presidents